<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<component type="desktop-application">
  <id>com.defold.Engine</id>
  <metadata_license>FSFAP</metadata_license>
  <project_license>LicenseRef-proprietary=https://defold.com/license/</project_license>
  <name>Defold Engine</name>
  <summary>The ultimate game engine for web and mobile</summary>

  <description>
    <p>
      Free to use:
      Defold is completely free to use with a developer-friendly license for both personal and commercial use.
    </p>
    <p>
      Games:
      Defold is used by game developers all over the world. It’s a proven tool for games of all genres.
    </p>
    <p>
      Performance first:
      Built from the ground up with a clear focus on performance. Spend time making games, not waiting for builds.
    </p>
  </description>

  <launchable type="desktop-id">com.defold.Engine.desktop</launchable>

  <screenshots>
    <screenshot type="default">
      <caption>Editor</caption>
      <image>https://defold.com/images/editor/nosetup-editor.png</image>
    </screenshot>
  </screenshots>

  <url type="homepage">https://defold.com/</url>

  <provides>
    <binary>Defold</binary>
  </provides>

  <releases>
    <release version="1.2.179" date="2021-02-08">
      <description>
Our iOS entitlements support was improved with a better way of merging the entitlements.

We’ve added a new error code to the return value of gui.new_texture().

We’ve updated/fixed some issues with regards to callstack output. This should help us pinpoint issues faster in the future.

We now publish the download link to the reference documentation 12 for each release on http://d.defold.com 13.

For native extensions and iOS, we added signing to the ./Frameworks folder (if there is one).
We also copy any swift libraries found in the frameworks folder to the ./SwiftSupport folder. These changes were made to support the latest Facebook sdk.

When bundling for Windows, bob.jar now only bundles one architecture at a time (32 or 64 bit).

Bob got an argument --exclude-build-folder which is a comma separated string of folders that should not be included in the build. 
      </description>
    </release>
  </releases>
</component>
